

## Chukwuemeka Maduekwe

Remotely Available Full Stack Developer











# Summary

I'm a proficient Full stack developer with hands-on experience designing, developing and debugging apps using a range of technologies and programming languages. I prefer the Functional paradigm over other paradigms, and I enjoy working on challenging but productive projects. I'm knowledgeable about Web, Mobile and Desktop development. I have confidence in my ability to build apps from scratch with little to no supervision, but, at the same time I enjoy collaboration with other developers.

# Preferred Tools

- Frontend: Redux, Next.js (React Framework) and Apollo
- **Desktop**: Electron.js
- **UI**: Material-UI, SASS/SCSS, and CSS3
- Backend: Express (Node.js Framework), Mongo DB, Firebase, and GraphQL
- Mobile: Flutter and React Native

## Experience

#### Frontend Developer at Zenith bank July 2022 till date

- Revamped existing applications at the same time reducing load time.
- Designed and developed user-friendly app, and improve performance.

#### Full Stack Developer at AlienForest (freelance) Oct 2018 - June 2022

- Trained aspiring developers on different topics relating to development
- Fixed bugs in existing websites and enhanced significant improvement
- Oversaw full lifecycle of webapp development for over 5 projects
- Created and published contents online
- Improved search engine optimization for existing and new sites

#### System Administrator at Nigeria Security Printing and Minting (intern) 2017

- Installation and configuration of software and hardware
- Manage network servers and setting up of accounts and workstations
- Troubleshoot issues, outages and train staff on new technologies
- Ensure security through access controls, backups and firewalls

### Education

Abia state University, Uturu

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (2014 to 2018)